ANKIT PATEL

Web Developer

ankitspatel1990@gmail.com - +1 (867) 689-9090 - Calgary, AB

Profile

Seeking Position in Information Technology Development by utilizing my technical skills and ability to create quality web software using my working experience in designing and developing website for over 2 years.

Over 3 years of hand on experience in creating and maintaining high quality websites. Functional knowledge of building personal landing pages and blogs. Knowledge of how to use modern development and designing technologies. Have Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering.

Skills

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript Node JS, Express JQuery, Angular 2+

C#, MVC, Agile Typescript, React MongoDB, MySQL, MS Access, Oracle

.net, Bootstrap, Font Awesome Git, GitHub, Heroku MS Visual Studio/Code, Eclipse

Other Skills

Focused and disciplined Quick Lerner Good Problem Solving Skill Communication skills (verbal, Oral)

Responsible with Work Ethics Effective Time Management Effective Teamwork skill

Related Experience

Web Developer, Self-Learning

Jun 2017 – Present Q Calgary, Canada

- Spent about 2 Years, Developing and Designing different Web application with my extensive knowledge of diverse technical skills and passion of always learning new technologies.
- Developed myPortfolio website to demonstrate my knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript And making advancement to upgrade website using knowledge of nodejs, Express, mongoDB and Bootstrap, Font Awesome
- o Developed simple authentication web application to utilize my additional knowledge of Body-parser, Passport
- Design Basic Movie Blog Application by applying my knowledge of Node, Express and mongoDB relating RESTful API
- Spending my knowledge of Angular JS and Angular 2+, developed BookKart and RecipeBook, single page applications respectively
- Deploy some of above applications using source control system such as git, Github and cloud platform like Heroku
- o Developed knowledge of different CLI covering angular CLI, Node CLI, AWS CLI and use npm, Powershell.
- During this Experience, Learn variety of IDE and Text Editors that includes cloud9, Sublime, Atom but mainly MS visual Code.

Jr. Web Developer, Bisag

May 2012 – Jul 2013 Ahmedabad, India

- Developed and design front end for more than 10 websites utilizing my extensive knowledge HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- o Integrate Database with Different website using knowledge of MySQL
- o Manage Documents for application solution and usability
- o Write Reports and Code in Professional manner

Java Developer Trainee, Bisag

Jan 2011 - May 2012 Ahmedabad, India

- Designed an Advanced Java based Networking Application using the incremental build model
- Designed a Software to help administrators to help them monitor and control the computers in the local area network
- Developed Software to monitor the applications and processes of computers connected in the local area network
- Developed Software to File Transfer and Communication among the computers Practiced MySQL as Database,
 Used Net Beans 7.1.1

Academic Experience

Park Smartly, Centennial College

- Developed and Design a Web Application to solve daily parking issues in multistory building.
- o Work on Project in Professional manner using Agile Software Development Methodology.
- Park Smartly is web application which utilizes the functions to find nearest parking space in large buildings and to find parked car. And to book online parking space and extend parking hours.
- Developed Application by applying extensive knowledge C#.net
- o Design application and Manage application data using CSS, MS SQL Server with use of MS Visual Studio

Online Movie Booking System, Centennial College

- o Developed and Design web application to book movie online and to cancel reservation of movie
- o Developed Web Application using my hands on experience of HTML, JavaScript
- o Designed Web Site using custom CSS, Bootstrap, Font Awesome
- o Managed Application Data using knowledge of MySQL
- o Practiced MS Visual Studio

Other Experience

Customer Service Representative/Server/Cashier, Pho Lien

Sep 2015 – Apr 2019 ♥ Whitehorse, Canada

Stock Associate, Walmart Canada

Oct 2015 - Jul 2016 Whitehorse, Canada

Supervisor, La Sani Grill

Oct 2013-Apr 2015 🗣 Toronto, Canada

Education

Centennial College, Software Engineering Technology

Sep 2013 – Apr 2015 Toronto, Canada

Gujarat Technological University, Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

Aug 2008 – May 2012

Gujarat, India

Courses/Certification

Angular 2+, Udamy, Whitehorse, 2019

Web Developer Bootcamp, Udamy, Whitehorse, 2018

Agile Crash Course, Udamy, Whitehorse, 2018

HTML, 2011, CDAC, India

C and C++ Language, 2010, CDAC, India